<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Fabien Bloume Blog</title>
        <link>https://nusantara-self.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Fabien Bloume Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The beauty in our world]]></title>
            <link>https://nusantara-self.github.io/blog/the-beauty-in-our-world</link>
            <guid>https://nusantara-self.github.io/blog/the-beauty-in-our-world</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<ReactPlayer]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="width:640px;height:360px" class="react-player"></div><p></p><p><strong>What an era we live in.</strong></p><p>Not sure if every human being on earth that existed over the thousands of years <em>(which is an insignifiant amount of time to be fair)</em> commonly felt that way about their era, but wow, guess we've found ourselves a winner, as I feel like we're in <strong>a truly special era</strong> of our humankind.</p><p>I'm a 95' kid, and I noticed the world switch.</p><p>Communication platforms were just single channels in <em>now-retro</em> TV, we had analog phones at best (<em>which was already incredible</em>). Now, we get to have immensely powerful computer chips in our pockets; occasionnally telling us what we should buy next and triggering bell sounds every now and then, making sure we stay "<em>connected</em>".</p><p>Our world completely transformed, <em>technologically</em>, <em>socially</em> for the better or worse. I'll stand with the better.</p><p>We have been <em>(unequally)</em> blessed with the <strong>ability to teleport</strong>. We literally have the ability to visit or live in <em>very, very</em> distant lands in less than a day. A land where no one lives the way we're used to, where people express differently in words and body language.
And.. we may stay in this land for short or long times, sometimes never even coming back. What would have been a trip of a lifetime earlier is possible today in a single day.
Knowing what's outside of our environment is now easier than ever.  Putting into perspective how cultures, beliefs and religions are all tied to the environment we grow up in.</p><p><strong>Anyone is free to learn anything</strong>. We <strong><em>almost equally have access</em></strong> to the <strong>most complete encyclopedias the world has known</strong>, search engines, making the most profound knowledge database accessible to the many. We also have the <strong>superpower to interact with physically distant people in real-time</strong>, even with people we may never even meet physically in our lifetime. Crazy.</p><p>We've got entire countries powered by electricity, to which the same physics principles can be applied to make electronic sounds translating into music. <a href="https://youtu.be/8W49pp_HN7w?t=134" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Playing single notes in divine symphony, creating the dream of a perfect melody</a>.</p><p>We are the generation of the infinite and finite, the generation of the all or nothing, the one that is about to have it all or destroy it all.
Our meaning is to strive for the better, take the advantage of each opportunities this craziness times bring to us.</p><p>At least we would have tried. And sometimes, trying is good enough.</p><p>And if one day the clock stops ticking, at least I'll have this content to be up till the end of times.. <em>or just till the end of this hosting platform.</em></p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2ZAWXs9QOfo&amp;t=28s" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Digital, digital, digital, I would never find another you</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>thoughts</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hello world!]]></title>
            <link>https://nusantara-self.github.io/blog/hello-world</link>
            <guid>https://nusantara-self.github.io/blog/hello-world</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[My name is Fabien, I'm a 27 years old cybersecurity engineer and.. this is my first blog post on here. :)]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My name is <strong>Fabien</strong>, I'm a <strong>27 years old cybersecurity engineer</strong> and.. this is my first blog post on here. :)</p><p>Most of my posts here will be <strong>tech-related</strong> and the main goal is to document my <strong>learning</strong> and <strong>exploration journey</strong>.</p><p>From time-to-time, some posts might be more <em>personal</em>, like <em>travel</em> or <em>music</em> related; I just hope to <strong>make of that space one that truly defines things I wish to share</strong> and I'm <strong>passionnate about</strong>. Making it as comfortable as I wish it to be. No worries, tagging <em>might</em> be used in order to separate those!</p><p>A documentation tab will also be present to allow for storing quick tips &amp; tricks on specific subjects : <strong>cloud</strong>, <strong>python</strong>, <strong>automation</strong>, <strong>security operations</strong> and so on.</p><p>If some things are useful to me, then they might be to you; welcome to my space.</p><p>Enjoy!</p><div style="width:640px;height:360px" class="react-player"></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>introduction</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>